Buddha was born in this world
2639 years ago.
Scriptures portray his birth
in a very mystical manner.
We don't know whether these descriptions
were based on truth
or fictionalized in later dates.
From a religious perspective, it can be
said that his birth was extraordinary.
because he was
an extraordinary person
From a historical perspective,
it can be said that
these descriptions were written
after the fact
to glorify Buddha's greatness.
They say that Buddha's mother
had a dream about his birth.
In her dream, music filled the skies.
and when she stepped outside,
she saw a bright star approaching her.
Then she noticed that the shining star
was actually a white elephant.
In India, a white elephant
is considered a good omen.
While ordinary elephants have 2 ivory
tusks, white elephants are said to have 6.
Hence they are
considered most sacred in India.
In her dream, this 6-tusked
white elephant descended from the sky.
It struck her on the right side of
her ribs and entered into her.
She was startled and woke from the dream
and afterwards she conceived a baby.
In those days in India, women
gave birth in their parents' house.
So Buddha's mother headed home
when she was 9 months pregnant.
Buddha's father was
the king Suddhodana.
He was from the Sakya clan, while
Buddha's mother was from the Koliya clan.
They were from two different clans
but there was a marital alliance
between the two.
Hence females from this clan would wed
males from the other clan, and vice versa.
The country was about the size of Kaya.
It was basically more of a tribal state,
rather than a developed kingdom.
It was a small country that
Buddha was born a crown prince.
His mother was
heading home to give birth.
The sun was shining hard midday,
so she came across a forest
and decided to take a rest.
That place is known as Lumbini.
She was resting in the hills of Lumbini,
where there was a grove of Ashoka trees.
The ashoka trees were
full of blossoms.
While enjoying them,
she found a beautiful blossom
and reached up with her right hand.
As she did, she felt labor pain.
A tent was set up quickly
and she gave birth to a baby.
The baby came out through
her right ribs, and not the usual way.
The gods of Heaven and Brahman came down
and caught the baby in a golden net.
And as the Dragon king came
and bathed the baby with water,
the baby’s body
shined with a golden glow.
This is how baby Buddha
was described in the scriptures.
Now they say the infant
stood right up
and walked seven steps
across all four directions.
After that, he stood pointing
one hand towards the sky
and the other towards the earth
and shouted "In the Heavens above and
Earth beneath, I alone am the Honored One.
All that exists
in the Three Worlds is suffering
but I will bring comfort to all."
Of course, he would have said this
in Indian language, not in Chinese.
He would've said it in Indian
but the scriptures we refer to
translate them in Chinese this way.
So that's the story of his birth.
When it says the baby shined
in a golden glow after a bath means
the baby was born human with human form,
but was indeed a Buddha.
Can this be real? Did he really
come out of his mother's right side?
Could she have had
a cesarean back then?
This story raises some questions.
Did he really walk seven steps?
And did an infant really talk?
The story raises many questions.
Some can believe the story without
any doubt, 'He's a sacred being after all.
Of course he was born differently',
this is called faith.
Is it wrong to have such faith?
Or is it okay?
It's okay to believe this. Why?
We have freedom to have faith.
So if some of us believe his birth story,
then it is out of the religious faith.
If some say "Unbelievable.
It can't be true.",
then does it imply
the lack of faith? No, it doesn't.
We have freedom
to believe or not to believe.
Those with faith
just believe the story.
For those who don't believe the story,
how would they take the story?
They can take them
as symbolic narratives.
During Buddha's time,
Indian people believed
social phenomena
in terms of the gods.
They believed that all things
have divine presence in them.
That's why the birth
was described like that.
So what does that mean? To be born
from his mother's right torso, this,
symbolizes that he is
from a royal background.
Because, in traditional Brahman beliefs,
the Brahmin god created this world,
and humans were his last creations.
Out of the god's mouth came
the Brahmin, class of priests.
Out of his torso, Kshatriya,
or the rulers and military elites emerged.
From his stomach, he created Vaishya,
the class of farmers and merchants.
And from his feet came the Shudra,
the class of slaves.
This is the origin of
India's four caste system.
The castes were basically
justified as god's creation.
Because of such myth,
the idea that
Buddha was born through
his mother's ribs means
he belonged to the royal class,
the Kshatriya.
Then what does it symbolize that
he walked seven steps on his own?
Traditional Indian culture has
a unique concept of reincarnation.
In this concept, there are more realms
between heaven and hell.
There are 6 realms in total.
They are Hell, the realm of
hungry ghosts, the realm of beasts,
the realm of fighting spirits,
the realm of human beings
and the land of heavenly beings.
One moves from one to another
in these six realms,
hence we call it
the 'Six realms of Samsara'.
As you see it's quite different
from western religions.
In the west once you go to Hell,
you stay there forever.
Once in Heaven, you're forever in Heaven.
This isn't all that rational, is it?
In such aspect,
Indian beliefs are more rational.
If you do good and go to heaven, you can
stay there until your good karma runs out.
If you do evil and go to hell, you stay
there until your punishment ends.
So we are all trapped
in this cycle through the 6 realms.
It's called the "wheel of life."
We cannot escape
this wheel of life.
Hence even if we go to Heaven,
it is not eternal.
The six steps Buddha took
refer to the six realms.
The fact that he took a seventh step
means that he stepped out of this cycle.
He had achieved Enlightenment
and reached Nirvana.
Through this, he was truly freed
from the cycle of life.
Nirvana refers to the state of
true happiness, free from all suffering.
Hence the story of his birth
was written to show that
Buddha was meant to achieve
Enlightenment and reach Nirvana.
We know he eventually
achieved Enlightenment,
hence stories are written to say
he was born to do so.
I'm a monk now, hence they'd say
I was destined to become a monk.
Fortune tellers say
'You'll die if you go somewhere',
hence we don't go there
and we don't die.
if we know the future in advance,
things become meaningless.
Nothing is predetermined.
So it's more logical to say that
Buddha's birth story was written later,
telling us that he was
born to become a Buddha.
So if I were to live my ordinary life
and do something extraordinary
before dying,
they'll probably say that
I too was born to do great things.
So the seven steps symbolize
stepping beyond the cycle of life
and becoming an Enlightened one.
Pointing toward the sky
and the earth, he shouted,
"In the Heavens above and Earth beneath,
I alone am the honored one.”
This is only the first part
of what he said.
Most people remember only this.
But you need to know the next clause.
"All that exists
in the Three Worlds is suffering,
but I will bring comfort to all."
People interpret the first clause
in a secular manner,
and think he was very egotistic
to say such things.
When he refers to the 'In the Heavens
above and Earth beneath',
he's actually referring to both
the land of Gods and land of Humans.
Saying he alone is the Honored One means
that he is the most precious among all.
He's referring to himself when saying
"I alone am the Honored One',
but this ultimately applies to us all.
Why? Because we are all
capable of becoming Buddha.
We all have it in ourselves
to become enlightened.
Hence he's basically declaring dignity
of all human beings.
Yet, do you consider yourself
the most precious being?
Buddha proclaimed that
across all heaven and earth,
he himself is
the most precious of them all.
In western world, they say human rights
are God-given, don't they?
When they say it's 'God-given',
they are putting God above Human.
Buddha's story is based on
a completely different approach.
Why? He's saying that
he himself is the most precious,
not just among Human
but also among land of Gods.
Now what is he referring to
as 'Earth beneath'?
He's referring to secular things.
First of all, money.
Are you more precious than money or not?
(Audience) We're more precious
than money.
Well, you say you are.
(Audience Laugh)
And yet if a company offers
to pay you $20,000 more,
do you jump at the opportunity or not?
Are you then not selling
yourself for money?
When getting married,
do you not marry a guy who earns more?
You all go for the money.
Even when a person dies,
what do we do?
Don’t insurance companies
put a price on death?
They pay more for plane crashes victims
and pay less for bus accidents victims.
In a way we're living in a world that
puts money first, not human beings.
In this world,
money is the most precious.
In the medieval period,
God came first.
Now, we live in a capitalist society,
where money comes above all of us.
But Buddha is saying the most precious
of all is not money, power, or fame.
It's not desire, pleasure,
ideology, faith, or god.
What is most precious?
I, myself is the most precious.
Do you live with
that level of self-awareness?
Do you consider yourselves precious?
Do you think you are
more precious than diamonds?
Not just yourself, but others as well?
Buddha's saying that all living beings
are the most precious,
every single one of them.
No belief is more precious
than life itself.
No ideology or belief can come above us.
This preciousness is not given
by another entity.
It is absolutely intrinsic to all beings.
Human beings come first
and only then comes ideology,
belief, moral, money, power, etc.
But in reality,
things don't work this way.
We've lost sight of
our own preciousness.
We've lost ourselves and put money,
ideologies, beliefs, status
and power above us.
In such, modern society
is called as an era of self-loss.
As we’ve lost ourselves, we're no longer
in charge of the house. Without an owner,
the house is taken over by thieves.
This is why our lives are in misery.
We take life so lightly
that we can kill ourselves.
We also can kill other people
so easily with guns and all.
Do you know how many
suicides occur daily?
On average, 43 people
commit suicide daily in Korea.
That is like a bus full of
people all dying from a crash.
This is all due to self-loss.
Buddha came to this world
to declare the dignity and
preciousness of all human lives.
He did so because these were not
recognized back then.
There is an anecdote about Buddha:
One day, while he was meditating, a group
of 30 young men came by and asked him.
"Have you seen a women
running away just now?"
"Why do you ask?"
Buddha said.
The young men had gone
on a picnic with their girlfriends.
After drinking and dancing,
they got drunk and passed out.
They woke up only to realize that
all their valuables had been stolen.
It turned out that one of
the men didn't have a girlfriend,
so he had paid a prostitute
to come to the picnic with him.
When everyone got drunk
and passed out,
that prostitute stole everyone's
valuables and ran away.
So they were asking Buddha
if he saw a woman running away.
Buddha looked at them,
smiled, and said,
"My friends, is it more important
to find your belongings,
or to find yourself?"
Although drunk, the men replied,
"Of course, it's more important
to find ourselves."
Then, Buddha told them
to come and sit with him.
What does this imply?
He was pointing out how they were fussing
over losing their belongings,
while they had actually lost themselves.
Buddha had them sit down
and spoke to them.
And the 30 men all came to realization
and they became monks
right then and there.
The scriptures say that
the youth back in those days
were quite the pleasure seekers.
When he was young, Buddha himself
enjoyed pleasurable things.
The story of the monk Yasa
also portrays this.
Yasa and his friends were drinking and
dancing at night and they fell asleep.
When Yasa woke up,
he saw in the candlelight
all his friends passed out.
The female dancers who looked
so beautiful the night before
were all sleeping too.
Some of them were snoring,
others had vomited next to them,
some were exposing their breasts,
others had their legs
on top of each other.
Back then in India, corpses of
the lowest class would get thrown out
in the woods without being cremated.
As they'd get thrown out, corpses would
all tangle on top of one another.
Yasa found his friends and
the beautiful dancers in the same way.
He thought, "Ah, what agony. How did
my ballroom become a graveyard?"
He eventually met Buddha
and became a monk.
In today's terms,
he was like the sole heir of
a conglomerate like Samsung.
The monk Yasa was
son of Guriga Jangja.
The scriptures contain
many stories like this.
They show us that youth back then
were pleasure seekers to a great extent.
Yasa had friends not only in his country
but also in other countries.
Seeing how a man like Yasa, who enjoyed
such luxurious life, could become a monk,
four of his friends assumed that surely
he must have been deceived and misled.
"Yasa would never become a monk;
he loves to party with us,"
the friends said.
When they went to rescue Yasa,
his friends met Buddha.
And they all became monks.
(Audience Laugh)
"This wizard must have some power.
Let's all go and rescue him",
said Yasa's 50 friends
from other countries.
They all went to rescue Yasa. They met
Buddha, and all became monks.
This is the famous story of
Yasa and his 54 friends.
Yasa and his 54 friedns,
as well as the 5 initial disciples,
became the 60 first disciples of Buddha.
Through them, Buddha declared
his willingness to spread his teachings.
I mention these stories to say that
people in Buddha's time were influenced
by materialism, power, desire,
money, and pleasure.
On the other hand,
there were religious folks
that were blindly faithful
to Brahman beliefs.
Regardless of the sin,
they'd believe they'd go to Heaven
as long as they bathe in the Ganges.
This is why Buddha mentioned both
'In the Heavens above and Earth beneath'.
There's another anecdote of Buddha.
One day, King Bimbisara asked himself
while studying Buddha's teachings.
'What is the most precious thing
in this world?'
He was a king and he had
a big house, precious jewels, swords,
carriages, horses, beautiful women, etc.
He wondered what could be
the most precious of them all.
If he had to choose just one,
everything felt too precious.
But they all felt like
nothing in a way too.
So he asked his wife Malike:
"What do you think is
the most precious in the world?"
Now, the right answer for a wife
to tell her husband would be,
"It is you and you alone."
Back in those days,
Kings ruled with absolute power.
And yet Malike responded,
"I've thought long and hard, I think
I myself am the most precious."
She could've been killed
for responding this way.
And yet the king said,
"Do you think so too? I agree,
I think I'm the most precious too."
So they went to Buddha with their story.
"We both thought about it long and hard.
We've concluded that we ourselves
are the most precious of all."
Buddha told them
they were correct indeed.
Nowadays, we don't realize
how precious we really are.
We call them, "common mortals."
who don’t know their preciousness.
You are all suffering.
Why do you suffer?
It's because you're
making yourself suffer.
When I ask, "why are you suffering?"
you say, "I broke up with my girlfriend."
So I ask, "why are you suffering
when you've broken up?"
"Because I've broken up, of course."
"No, but why are you suffering
for having broken up?"
"Gosh, Sunim, you don't know anything.
You've never dated," they say.
"It doesn't matter if I've dated or not.
The question is, why are you suffering for
having broken up? Is your ex-girlfriend
stealing from you? Is she hitting you?
Why does the break-up
make you suffer?"
"How can I not suffer
after a break-up?"
As you see, we cannot have
a conversation. (Audience Laugh)
I ask why he's suffering and
he asks how it is possible not to suffer.
So I say, "Do you need a new girlfriend?
If so, meet someone else.
If not, don't. Why is this
something to suffer over?"
"If she's with you, you're stuck
with her for the rest of your life.
Now that she's out of the picture,
you can meet new girls.
It's an opportunity.
I'd be grinning if I were you."
He says he's suffering
because of the break-up,
but he's actually suffering
because he thinks he has to.
Hence he says
"How can I not suffer?"
So after a few tries I say,
"Well just go on and suffer then.
If you enjoy suffering,
suffer all you want."
He's tormenting himself.
He's giving himself an excuse to suffer.
This is losing oneself.
If we really hold ourselves precious,
why would we torment ourselves?
And yet we don't even realize
we're tormenting ourselves.
We consider ourselves as inferior,
we call ourselves ugly and we suffer.
We don't know
how precious we really are.
When Buddha came to this world and
declared he alone is the Honored One,
he means that each of us is the most
precious and the most honored one.
There is nothing that can replace us.
And yet we don't live our lives this way.
We sell ourselves for a few bucks,
we sell ourselves for ideology and belief.
We live with no conscience awareness.
Once we truly realize
how precious we are,
we can no longer suffer
even if we want to.
We call such a state of
no suffering as 'Nirvana',
and a state of freedom
from bondage as ‘enlightenment’.
The one who attains
this state is Buddha.
Buddha is the master of his own destiny,
the master of the universe.
We all have the right and
potential to become one.
And yet we give it all up
and live like slaves.
We should first and foremost
never abuse ourselves.
Regardless of whether we are black
or white, male or female,
with or without disability, tall or short,
regardless of our childhood experiences.
When a child is born,
is he born into this world
only through proper marriage?
only through when you
meet a desired spouse?
He can be born into this world
through rape as well, can he not?
From a mother's point of view,
she says "I didn't want this.
I wasn't married, I was raped."
But from the child's perspective,
does it make any difference?
Is it logical, then,
to discriminate children
because they are black, slaves,
children of prostitutes
or single moms? Is it logical?
Nonetheless our society
discriminates, does it not?
We are absolute precious beings.
Ethics, morals, traditions
cannot deny our very own dignity.
Some babies are born with
male and female genitalia.
Some are born without either.
Are they being punished for
their bad deeds from former life?
Is it God's punishment?
Some children are born homosexual.
They don't choose to be homosexual
but their inclinations just work this way.
Hating homosexuals is
against the way of nature.
In Christian terms, homophobia is
against God's order of creation.
If we're all God's creation,
homosexuals are created by God as well.
If we say homosexual people
are God’s mistakes,
then we're saying God makes mistakes,
that he is fallible. Right?
Any act of discrimination toward
anybody violates the truth.
This is the meaning
of Buddha's first words,
"In the Heavens above
and Earth beneath,
I alone am the honored one.”
I am the most Precious One.
And yet we don't live our lives this way.
Today, on Buddha's birthday,
we need to remember this truth.
We should all recognize
how precious we are.
It doesn't matter whether
you're married or not, young or old,
with our without disabilities.
If you're missing an arm,
that just makes life uncomfortable.
That doesn't make you inferior.
It should no longer matter
who your parents are
or you are illegitimate,
not any more.
Now, the clause that follows
the first one is very important.
"All that exists in the Three Worlds is
suffering, but I will bring comfort."
The Three Worlds refers to the whole
world. Everyone in this world.
"All that exists is suffering." Why?
Because we have lost ourselves.
Hence, Buddha is saying he has come
to bring comfort to all beings.
He's not saying he alone will become
Buddha and live a free and happy life.
As a free and happy being,
he's saying he would guide others
towards the same path.
In Christian terms, he's saying he'll
spread the gospel, the good news.
Buddha says you should first
become a free and happy being.
Then, you should help others
become free and happy too.
Buddha's speech upon
his birth represents
the fact that he lived
his life with such purpose.
He became happy and
he led others to be happy.
In the same sense,
what does Jungto vow to do?
We vow to live as free individuals
without suffering
and contribute to the world around us.
In Mahayana Buddhism,
this is expressed as
上求菩堤 下化衆生 (sanggubori hahwajungsaeng)
"To seek enlightenment from above
while helping others from below"
There are no differences in caring for
oneself and caring for others.
The two happens simultaneously.
One does not come before the other.
Buddha's birth story represents
this singular purpose of
the life he lived.
On Buddha's birthday,
we need to remember his teachings.
Even in material abundance,
we live in era of self-loss.
There are three losses:
losing ourselves as individuals,
losing the sense of community
and losing the natural environment.
These are the three major maladies
afflicting modern society.
Loss of self, loss of community,
loss of nature.
The very first step to recover
these is to recover the 'self'.
You should first all be happy
and free, whatever you do.
And that happiness must go
beyond the individual into the community.
This helps us recover
the sense of community.
No longer cause harm
to others for my own benefit.
What I do benefits both you and me.
We both benefit from my actions.
And as we recover the sense of community,
we should stop destroying our environment.
By destroying our environment,
we are hurting ourselves, it is wrong.
We need to coexist
with nature in harmony.
We call this sustainable development.
There is a limit to development
by destroying nature.
Hence in order to continue our existence,
we need to coexist with nature.
This is the path we should take
as we recover from modern society's ills.
This is what Buddha proclaimed at birth.
He declared it 2600 years ago.
There are hundreds of millions
more Buddhists nowadays,
and yet things haven't changed since.
We call ourselves Buddhists only by name.
We aren't following his words.
We pray only for money,
possessions, and spouses.
We pray to do well
on exams, to get elected, etc.
We are seeking from him
for secular desires.
This has nothing to do with
Buddha's teachings.
So the fact that there are
more Buddhists now
does not mean that
there are more happy people
or that the world is a better place.
Then what good is increasing
the number of Buddhist?
To compete with
the number of Christians?
We need to work on our quality as
Buddhists. When we follow his teachings,
it's a good thing
if we increase in number.
But if we forget
what Buddha taught for us,
increase in size means nothing.
In today's society,
people even ask me,
"Sunim, how is your temple doing?"
What do they mean by "doing well"?
It means many devotees.
The temple also needs to have
a lot of money, right?
The temple also needs
a big building, right?
How is this question different from
"How is your company doing?",
"How is your shop doing?"
This question about your shop means
if there are many customers
and a lot of income.
It's all the same. It's because
we live in a Capitalist society.
Even religions have lost
their directions.
In a Capitalist world, religions
follow the capitalist way.
We say that socialist religion
is not religion
and that North Korea has no religion.
We say Juche ideology has
enslaved North Koreans.
It's true. North Korea
doesn't have religion.
They are enslaved
to the Juche ideologies.
And yet there’s no difference.
How our religions are enslaved
under Capitalist ideologies.
Some people even argue
whether you can make more money
by being Buddhist or Christian
There is only one religion in our country.
We believe in the religion of money.
Under the umbrella of money,
we open shops of Christianity,
Buddhism, etc. and compete for money.
We have a monotheistic society.
The same as North Koreans.
What is that religion?
The religion of money and capital.
We assess our world as such.
Give a loved one a present.
Even when a mother gives her child
a present, what does the child say?
"Mom, how much did this cost?"
We calculate love in monetary terms.
When someone buys us clothes or shoes,
what is the first thing we ask them?
"How much did you pay for this?"
Don’t we ask that?
If it's expensive, it's good.
If it's cheap, it's bad.
We're brainwashed with capitalism
without realizing it.
Just like North Koreans being
brainwashed with their ideology.
We have lost ourselves.
We need to find ourselves again.
This, Buddha has declared at birth.
This is why Buddha came
to this world on this very day.
Are these stories meaningful to you?
Or would you rather hear stories on
how to make more money?
In honor of Buddha's birthday,
we need to reflect on our attitude
toward the minorities in our society.
We tend to discriminate these people
without knowing,
like North Korean defectors,
Chinese Koreans,
Vietnamese workers, refugees etc.
I met those with disabilities
a few days back - the blind,
the deaf, and the crippled.
They feel an enormous
amount of discrimination.
I talk to North Korean defectors
and they confess how hard
it is to live in South Korea.
When we ask ourselves and
don't think we discriminate them.
Men never think
they discriminate against women
and yet women feel
they are discriminated.
There was a recent protest
held by LGBT folks,
and did we not discriminate
and show disgust towards them?
This is all wrong.
We should think that all beings born on
this earth are precious in their own way.
We should especially be more
considerate towards minorities
in terms of how we speak
to and treat them.
This is my request to you
in honor of Buddha's birthday.